Hey,gorgeous! How's it going?
帅哥，怎么样?
Dehydrated Japanese noodles under fluorescent lights.
萤光灯下的脱水日本面
Does it get better than this?
我能有多好?
Question: Are you dating anyone?
问你一个问题 你目前没有约会的对象吧?
I met somebody who would be perfect for you.
我遇见一个和你是绝配的人
Perfect might be a problem.
绝配或许是个问题
Had you said codependent or self-destructive....
你若说共同独立或自我毁灭的话…
-You want a date Saturday? -Yes,please.
-周六想要有个约会的对象吗? -当然，拜托了
He is cute.
他人帅
-He's funny. He's -He's a he?
-而且风趣，他… -你说的是“他”?
Well,yeah.
好吧，是的
Oh,God! I just
糟了，我以为…
You' re nice Oh,God.
你是个有为的青年
Good,Shelly. I' m gonna flush myself down the toilet now.
很好,雪莉,我要到马桶去把自己冲掉
Okay. Bye-bye.
再见
The One Where Nana Dies Twice
六人行 第1季 第08集 （祖母）娜娜死了两回
-=BT之家DRM小组 http://bbs.btbbt.com=- 荣誉出品 河马根据网络字幕微调制作
It's hard to enjoy noodles after that. Is that ridiculous?
听完后我没心情吃面了 这不荒谬吗?
Can you believe she actually thought that?
你能相信她会有这样的想法吗?
Yeah.
能
When I first met you, I thought maybe...
我第一次见到你时 我以为你是
... possibly...
…可能…
...you might be.
…也许
You did?
你真的这样认为?
You spent Phoebe's birthday party talking to my breasts...
对，但后来你在菲比的生日会上 一直盯着我的胸部
...so I figured maybe not.
…我想你大概不是吧
Did any of the rest of you guys think that when you first met me?
你们第一次看见我时 也是这样认为?
-I did. -I think so,yeah.
-我是 -我也是
-Not me. -No,no,me neither.
-我不是 -不，我也不这么认为
Although back in college, Susan Saladore did.
虽然大学时代的苏珊 这样认为
You' re kidding.
开什么玩笑?
-Did you tell her I wasn't? -No.
-你有告诉她我不是吗? -没有
I wanted to go out with her too.
因为我也想跟她约会
I told her you were seeing Bernie Spellman...
我告诉她你和伯尼是一对
...who also liked her.
因为他也喜欢她
Well,this is fascinating.
所以,这简直是太神奇了
So what is it about me?
是什么原因?
I don't know. You' re smart,you' re funny....
我不知道 因为你既聪明又风趣
So is Ross. Ever think that about him?
罗斯也是聪明又风趣 你们有想过他是吗?
-Yeah,right! -What is it?
-是哦 -到底是为什么?
I don't know. You just You have a quality.
我也说不上来 但你就是有那种潜质
-Yes,exactly. -Yeah,a quality.
-没错 -是的.潜质
"A quality. " Good. I was worried you were gonna be vague about this.
潜质?说得好 我还担心你们看不出呢
I think this is gonna work for you.
我想对你应该有用
-Excuse me? -Sure,sure.
-对不起 -好吧,好吧
Women find you less threatening, they let their guards down...
女人没有威胁 护花使者就没有机会啊…
...you' re like a stealth heterosexual.
…你就像一个偷偷摸摸的异性恋者
-It's Paolo calling from Rome. -Oh,my God! Calling from Rome!
-瑞秋，是保罗从罗马打来的 -天啊，从罗马打来
So he's calling from Rome. I could do that.
了不起，他从罗马打来 我也可以
Just gotta go to Rome.
我到罗马去就是了
Your Dad just beeped in. Can you make it quick?
摩妮卡，你爸打来的 你能长话短说吗?
I'm talking to Rome.
我正和罗马通电话
Hey,Dad. What's up?
爸，怎么了?
Oh,God.
我的天
Ross,it's Nana.
罗斯，是奶奶
-How you doing? -Hey,Dad.
-你们还好吧? -嗨,爸爸
So how is she doing?
她的情况如何?
The doctor says it's a matter of hours.
医生说只剩几小时了
-How are you,Mom? -Me? I' m fine,fine.
-妈,你还好吧? -我?我还好
I' m glad you' re here.
真高兴见到你们来
-What's with your hair? -What?
-你的头发怎么了? -什么?
-What's different? -Nothing.
-看起来有点不同 -没什么变化呀
Oh,maybe that's it.
或许是这个缘故
-She's unbelievable. Her mother's -Okay,relax.
-她真是令人难以置信 -放松点
We' re gonna be here a while.
看来我们得在这儿待一段时间了
We still have boyfriends and your career to cover.
免不了还要谈你男友和工作的事
Oh,God!
我的老天
The fuzzy little mints at the bottom of her purse.
她皮包里有发霉的钱币
Yeah,they were gross.
真呕心
You know what I love?
你们知道我喜欢什么吗?
Her Sweet 'N Lows.
她的人工袋糖
How she was always stealing them from restaurants.
她总是从餐厅里偷走
Not just from restaurants, from our house.
不只是餐厅,我们家也一样
Mrs. Geller?
格雷太太
She looks so small.
她看起来好小
I know.
我知道
Well,at least she's with Pop-Pop and Aunt Phylis now.
至少她现在有阿公和菲力斯婶婶陪伴
Aunt Phylis is dead?
菲力斯婶婶死了?
Yeah,for like six years.
是的,大概有差不多六年了
Where were? Can we focus,please?
-我在哪里? -说道哪里了?我们不要跑题,行不行?
Goodbye,Nana.
别了，奶奶
Bye,Nana.
再见，奶奶
Nurse!
护士!
What is going on?
到底怎么回事?
You know how the nurse said Nana had passed?
护士说她已过世了
Well,she's not quite.
实际上不是
What?
什么?
She's not passed! She's present! She's back!
她还没完全过世 她还活着，她回来了
What's going on?
怎么回事?
She may have died.
她可能死了
She may have died?
她可能死了?
We're looking into it.
我们正等着消息
I'll go see.
我进去看看
This almost never happens.
这种事几乎不可能发生
Now she's passed.
她过世了
I just have to know,okay?
我必须要知道
Is it my hair?
是我的头发?
Yes,that's exactly what it is. It's your hair.
对，正是你的头发
Yeah,you have homosexual hair.
你有一头同性恋的头发
So did she...?
她怎么样了?
Twice.
两次
-Twice? -Oh,that sucks.
-两次? -见鬼
-You guys okay? -I don't know. It's weird.
-你们还好吧? -说不上来，好诡异
I know she's gone, but I just don't feel....
我知道她已过世 但我感觉…
Maybe she's not really gone.
或许是因为她还没有
No,no,she's gone.
不，她过世了
We checked.
我们检查了
A lot.
好多遍
No,I mean,maybe no one ever really goes.
或许人不会真正过世
Ever since my mom died, every now and then...
我妈死后,我偶尔…
... I get this feeling that she's right here,you know?
…会感觉她就在身旁
And Debbie,my friend from junior high...
还有黛比,我初中最要好的朋友
...got struck by lightning on a miniature golf course.
在打迷你高尔夫时,被闪电击中
I always get this strong Debbie vibe...
用那枝黄色铅笔时…
...when I use a little yellow pencil.
…我总感到一股强烈的“心灵感应”
-I miss her. -Here,Pheebs.
-我好想念她 -来，菲此
Want this?
你要吗?
-Oh,thanks. -Sure.
-谢谢 -不客气
I just sharpened her this morning.
早上刚削好的
I don't believe any of that. When you' re dead...
我不信这一套
...you' re dead. You' re gone. You' re worm food.
人死了就是死了 死了就成了虫的食物
So Chandler looks gay,huh?
钱德看起来像个同性恋?
I don't know who this is, but it's not Debbie.
我不知道此人是谁 但绝对不是黛比
Dad,let's just make a decision.
爸爸，我们需要做个决定
You're right. It's going into the ground.
你是对的，要把她埋在土里
We should get the most basic thing.
我们应该把基本的东西弄好
"The non-protective corrugated fiberboard with white laminate. "
“上面有白色薄片的，不受保护的波纹纤维板”
Dad,we can't bury Nana in a dresser from kea.
爸爸，我们不能把奶奶穿的像一只食肉鹦鹉
This is why your mother buys my clothes.
这就是你妈妈买了我的衣服的原因
I hate to shop. I hate it.
我讨厌买东西，讨厌
Isn't this more about the fact that...
这是不是就是梦想成真
...once you decide,it's like acknowledging Nana's actually gone?
就像是知道奶奶真的走了一样
No,I really hate to shop.
不是，我只是讨厌买东西
-I thought it'd be a closed casket. -lt doesn't mean she can't look nice.
-我以为要用密封的棺木 -这并不代表,她不能看起来体面一点
Sweetie,you think you can get in there?
孩子，你想你能进去吗?
I don't see why not.
当然可以
Here's my retainer.
我的牙齿矫正器
I was just thinking...
我在想…
-...when my time comes -Dad.
-…我走的时候 -爸
Listen to me.
听我说
When my time comes, I wanna be buried at sea.
我走的时候,我要海葬
You what?
什么?
I wanna be buried at sea. It looks like fun.
我要海葬,好像挺有意思的
Define "fun. "
定义一下“有意思”
Come on. You'll make a day of it. You'll get a boat,pack a lunch....
那一天你们会玩得很开心的 你们会乘着船带着午餐…
And then we throw your body in the water. Gee,that does sound fun.
然后把你的尸体丢人大海 真是有意思
Everyone thinks they know me. Everyone says I'm so predictable.
每个人都自认为了解我 他们都说杰克太一成不变了
Maybe after I'm gone,they'll say, " Buried at sea? Huh? "
或许我死后他们会说 海葬,哈?
That's probably what they'll say.
他们大概会这么说吧
I'd like that.
希望如此
-Hey,gorgeous. -Hey.
-美女 -嘿
Look,l' m sorry about yesterday.
昨天的事很抱歉我
Don't worry. Apparently,other people have made the same mistake.
别担心,相信我 显然别人也犯了相同的错误
Okay. Phew!
好吧,咻!
So,what do you think it is about me?
为什么你认为是我的缘故?
I don't know what.
我说不上来
You just have...
你就是有那种…
-...a quality. -A quality. Great.
-…潜质 -潜质，是哦
It's a shame. You and Lowell would've made a great couple.
真可惜，因为你和罗尔本来很登对
Lowell? Financial Services Lowell? That's who you saw me with?
罗尔?会计部门的罗尔 你觉得我们很配?
What? He's cute.
有何不可?他很帅
Well,yeah.
而且
He's no Brian in Payroll.
他不像布莱恩
Is Brian?
布莱恩是不是…?
I don't know. If you were gonna set me up...
重点是如果你想替我配对
... I'd like to think it'd be with somebody like him.
我希望你会挑他
Brian's a little out of your league.
我想你配不上布莱恩
Excuse me. You don't think I could get a Brian?
对不起,你认为我配不上他?
Because I could get a Brian. Believe you me.
因为我配得上他,相信我
I'm really not.
我真的配不上
This one?
这一个?
I've shown you every dress we have.
我已让你们看过每件衣服
Unless you want her to spend eternity in a lemon-yellow pantsuit...
除非你们想让她永远穿着柠檬黄长裤
...go with the burgundy.
配上紫红色衣服
Whatever we pick,she'd say it's the wrong one.
不论我们选什么 她都会说我们选错了
Right. We'll go with the burgundy.
没错，就选紫红色吧
A fine choice. I'm coming out.
不错的选择，我要出来了
Wait! We need shoes.
等等，还缺鞋子
-How about these? -That's really a day shoe.
-这一双如何? -这是一双日鞋
Where she's going everyone else will be dressier?
她去的地方 大家会穿得更正式?
Could we see something in a slimmer heel?
能找鞋跟细一点的鞋吗?
I have nothing in an evening shoe in the burgundy.
我找不到紫红色的晚鞋
I can show you something silver that may work.
不过有双银色的鞋或许适合
-No,it really should be burgundy. -Unless we go with a different dress.
-不行，一定要紫红色 -除非我们另找一件套装
No,no,no. Watch this.
不,等等,我看看
Wait,I may have something in the back.
后面或许有
Oh,my God.
天呀
Is everything all right?
你没事吧，孩子?
Just Nana's stuff.
没事，只是奶奶的东西
You guys ready?
各位如何?准备好了没?
Mom called to tell me not to wear my hair up.
早上妈来电叫我别扎头发
-Know my ears aren't my best feature? -Some days it's all I can think about.
-我的耳朵并不是我最漂亮的部位吗? -有时候我认为是
I' m sorry l' m late. I couldn't find my bearings.
抱歉，我迟到了 我找不到我的“耳圈”
You mean your earrings?
你是指你的耳环?
What did I say?
我刚说什么?
-Are these the shoes? -Yes. Paolo sent them from ltaly.
-你穿这一双? -对，保罗从意大利寄来的
What? We don't have shoes here?
我们这儿没卖鞋子?
-Morning. We ready to go? -Don't we look nice all dressed up?
-早安，准备走了没? -穿戴整齐后,我们是不是都好看许多?
It's stuff like that,isn't it?
人模人样的，不是吗？
-lt was a really beautiful service. -lt really was.
-刚刚的仪式简单而隆重 -可不是吗
Come here,sweetheart.
过来，心肝
You know,I think it's time for you to start using night cream.
你该使用夜霜了
What?
什么?
Nothing. Just that your coat sounds like Brent Musberger.
没什么,只是你的外套很吵
-Check it out. Giants-Cowboys. -You're watching football at a funeral?
-瞧，巨人队对牛仔队 -你在葬礼时看足球赛?
No,it's the pre-game. I' m gonna watch it at the reception.
不，这还只是热身 我要在接待会上看比赛
You're a frightening,frightening man.
你真是个恶劣的人
Oh,no! My new Paolo shoes!
不，保罗送我的新鞋
I hope they're not ruined.
希望没坏
God,what a great day!
多美好的一天啊
What? Weather-wise.
什么?我是指天气
I know.
我知道
The air,the trees.
对，空气，树木
Even though Nana's gone, there's something almost life
即使奶奶已过世,就好像…
Ross,are you okay?
罗斯，你还好吧?罗斯…
No,l' m fine.
我没事
Just...
只是…
... having my worst fear realized,but....
…我最大的梦魇终於成真,但是…
I' m just checking to see if the muscle's in spasm.
别担心,我只是看看你是否肌肉痉挛
-What? What is it? -You missed a belt loop.
-怎么了? -你的皮带穿孔掉了一个
Okay,it's in spasm.
是痉挛
Here,sweetie. I took these when I had my gall thing accident.
来,孩子,我擦伤时都用这个
Thanks,Mom.
妈，谢谢
Sorry.
抱歉
Hi,l' m Andrea.
我叫安朵拉
I'm Dorothy's daughter.
桃乐丝的女儿
Hi,I'm Chandler,and I have no idea who Dorothy is.
我叫钱德,我不知道桃乐丝是谁
Look who's up!
看看谁出现了
-How do you feel? -I feel great.
-感觉如何? -感觉好多了…
I feel great. I feel great.
感觉好多了…感觉好多了…
Wow,those pills really worked.
那些药丸可真有效
Yeah. Not the first two, but the second two....
对，不是第一次那两颗 而是后来那两颗
I love you guys.
我爱你们大家
You guys are the greatest. I love my sister.
你们是最棒的 我爱我的妹妹
I love Pheebs.
我爱菲此
That's so nice.
你真好
I love you,man.
钱德，我爱你
And listen, if you wanna be gay,be gay!
听着,如果你想当同志,就当吧
It doesn't matter to me.
我不在乎
You were right.
你说得对
I do love you.
我最爱你了
Oh,Ross. I love you too.
哦,罗斯,我也爱你
Oh,no,I really love you.
哦,不,我真的爱你
I really love you.
我真的爱你
Oh,you don't get it!
哦,你没有明白
-What do you got there? -Just a hearing disability.
-那是什么? -我听力不好
What's the score?
比分多少?
1 7-1 4,Giants. Three minutes to go in the third.
巨人队以17比14领先 第三节只剩3分钟结束
Beautiful!
好极了
Pheebs,could you maybe hand me a cracker?
菲此，能拿块饼乾给我吗?
Your grandmother would've hated this.
你奶奶一定不喜欢的
Sure. What with it being her funeral and all.
当然，这是她的葬礼
No,I'd be hearing about...
我听到的是
...why didn't I get the honey-glazed ham.
“我为何没有糖浆火腿?”
Or I didn't spend enough on flowers. Or she'd say:
或是“我买的花不够”
"Why waste your money? I don't need flowers,l' m dead. "
又或许是,“何必花那么多钱，我死了不需要花”
That sounds like Nana.
口气像奶奶
Do you know what it's like to grow up...
知道和批评你每句话的人…
...with someone who is critical of every single thing you say?
…在一起生活是什么滋味?
I can imagine.
我可以想像
It's a wonder your mother turned out...
告诉你，我希望你妈会成为…
...to be the positive, life-affirming person she is.
…一个像她一样乐观、积极的人
That is a wonder.
真是个奇迹
So tell me something,Mom. If you had to do it all over again...
妈，告诉我 如果可以重来
... I mean,if she was here right now...
如果此时她在这儿
...would you tell her?
你会告诉她吗?
T ell her what?
告诉她什么?
How she drove you crazy, picking on every little detail.
她如何使你抓狂 挑剔每一件事
Like your hair,for example.
例如你的头发
I'm not sure I know what you're getting at.
我不懂你在说什么
Would things have been better if you'd just told her the truth?
难道你不认为说出实话 情况会改善吗?
Some things are better left unsaid.
我认为某些事最好还是不要说
It's nicer when people just get along.
家和万事兴
More wine?
再来些酒,亲爱的
Oh,I think so.
我也这么认为
Those earrings look really lovely on you.
你戴这副耳环真好看
Thank you.
谢谢
They're yours.
你给我的
Actually,they were Nana's.
其实是奶奶的
Now l' m depressed!
真叫人难过
Even more than I was.
此刚才还难过
Oh,look. My first grade picture.
哦,快看,我的一年级照片
Please ignore the Dy-no-mite T -shirt.
请略过Dynomite T恤衫
-Hey,who's this little naked guy? -That little naked guy would be me.
-这个光屁股的是谁? -那个人就是我
Look at the little thing!
瞧那个小东西
Yes,fine. That is my penis.
对，那是我的小弟弟
Can we be grownups now?
成熟点行吗?
Who are those people?
那些人是谁?
-Got me. -That's Nana right there in the middle.
-可把我问倒了 -中间那一个是奶奶
Yeah,let's see.
我看看
" Me and the gang at Java Joe's. "
“我和大伙儿摄於在爪哇乔家”
You look just like your grandmother. How old was she?
摩妮卡,你和你奶奶长得一模一样 当时她几岁?
Let's see," 1 939. "
1939年…39年
Twenty-four,twenty-five.
24或25岁
It looks like a fun gang.
他们好像玩得很开心
Look,look,look! I got Monica naked!
看…光屁股的摩妮卡
Let me see!
我看看
No,no. That would be me again.
不，还是我
I'm just trying something.
我在尝试新事物
Hey,Lowell.
罗威
Oh,hey,Chandler.
钱德
So how's it going in Financial Services?
会计部门的情况如何?
It's like Mardi Gras without the papier-mache heads.
就像是斋月前一天没有纸头(简直一团乱)
How about you?
你呢?
Good. Good. Listen...
好的，听着…
...I don't know what Shelly told you about me,but...
我不知道雪莉如何对你说我这个人…
... I' m not.
…但是我不是
I know. That's what I told her.
我知道，我也是这样告诉她的
Really?
真的?
So you can tell?
你看得出来?
Pretty much. Most of the time. We have a kind of radar.
十之八九 我们有某种…雷达
So you don't think I have...
这么说你认为我…
...a quality?
…没那种潜质
Speaking for my people, I'd have to say no.
代表男同志发言 我得说没有
By the way,your friend Brian, from Payroll? He is.
对了,你朋友布莱恩,他是
-He is? -And way out of your league.
-他是? -而且你配不上他
Out of my league!
我配不上他
I could get a Brian. If I wanted to get a Brian,I could get a Brian.
我可以得到布莱恩 如果我愿意
Hey,Brian.
Hey, Brian. 你好,布莱恩